Kevin Herrarte

Systems Engineer



Innovative software engineer offering eight years of experience in the full software development lifecycle, from concept through delivery of web and mobile oriented solutions. Expert in advanced methodologies, tools and processes contributing to the design and rollout of software applications

TECHNICAL TOOLS.

Javascript, Typescript, AngularJS, React, ¡Query, HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Less,

NodeJS, C#, ASP.NET, Java, Spring Framework, PHP, Laravel,

MySQL, Microsoft SQL Server, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis, Firebase, Amazon Web Services, Azure, Jenkins, SCRUM Methodologies, Sketch App, Photoshop, Illustrator.

Work experience

Autoweb Inc.

2016 - Present

Software Engineer

Provide object-oriented software design; developing and supporting a CMS web solution. Autoweb is an automotive media and marketing services company leader in North America.

- Lead front end developer optimizing UI/UX
- Maintain and deploy code to Production environments following approval of customer.
- Research and propose appropriate technologies for ongoing and new projects.
- Introduced methodologies and best practices that enhanced product definition, release processes and customization of applications to user needs.
- Refactor and optimize JavaScript solutions to deliver high-performance software.

Research Mobile

2011 - 2015

Software Engineer

Lead front end developer of an international company that provides technological solutions to big customers.

- Contributed software engineering expertise in the development of products through the software lifecycle, from requirements definition through successful deployment.
- Planned and estimated tech/human resources for projects based on customers priorities
- Designed web and mobile UI focused on usability and minimalism.
- Helped build and enhance highly available, scalable, real-time and secure systems used by
- Completed eight major projects, working closely with agile development team to develop, test and maintain Web- and mobile-based software applications.
- Adhered to high-quality development standards while delivering solutions on-time and onbudget.

Education

Pluralsight

2017 - Present

Certifications

- Advanced Node.js
- Basics React.js
- Practical Design Patterns in Javascript
- Javascript Best Practices
- Developer to Architect

Universidad Mariano Gálvez

2016 - 2016

Postgraduate Degree

Information Technologies

Universidad Mariano Gálvez

Bachelor of Science

Systems Engineering

2009 - 2013